

□ (+91) 8939308144 | ■ naveenvignesh5.nv@gmail.com | • naveenvignesh5 | • naveenvigneshb

Summary_

Full stack developer with 4+ year experience. Worked on react, node.js, express, angular, typescript. Experienced in java, spring-boot. Experienced in cross platform mobile application development using frameworks like react-native, ionic-capacitor, cordova. Into open source development, and have made contribution by publishing some well used NPM packages in react-native. Intermediate level of expertise in data structures and algorithms.

Skills

Front-end React, React Native, Angular, Vue, HTML / CSS3, SASS / SCSS

Back-end Node.js, Express, Spring boot

Devops Docker, CircleCI

Programming Javascript, Typescript, Java, Python

Miscellaneous Git, Agile, Scrum, LateX

Languages Tamil, English

Work Experience __

PwC - ANZ Bangalore, India

SOFTWARE CONSULTANT Nov. 2020 - Current

- · Worked on online credit profile tool written in react, typescript, converting business needs into usable solutions.
- · Worked on back-end solutions written as micro services in java, spring boot, Node.js for providing APIs with SQL and MongoDB databases.
- · Worked on standalone reusable component framework in react for used across multiple UI modules using reactstrap, storybook.

HODL Media Inc. Palo Alto, California, United States

Oct. 2022 - Jan 2023 FRONT-END ENGINEER

- Working as front-end engineer responsible for mobile application development.
- Main work includes working on company's core mobile application in react-native stack.
- · Contribute to back end API development occasionally which is written in node.js stack with SQL database.

Intellect Design Arena Chennai, India (WFH)

MOBILE APPLICATION DEVELOPER (FREELANCER)

Mar. 2022 - Current

- Developed a mobile application for data extraction from id and passports using ionic-capacitor stack.
- Converted data science modules into usable modules for android and iOS mobile applications.
- Developed native capacitor modules for OCR, document detection, image processing using android java using libraries like Tesseract, Pytorch, OpenCV.
- · Developed web applications based on vuejs (vue3) front-end and node.js express.js backend with mongo database

5datainc Hyderabad, India (WFH)

FRONT END DEVELOPER (FREELANCER)

MEMBER TECHNICAL STAFF

Nov. 2021 - Jun. 2022

Jan. 2019 - Nov. 2020

- · Implemented front-end solutions in react for data science and survey applications using react, survey.js, material-ui.
- Implemented front-end solutions for pulsesg sass product using stacks like react, ag-grid, material-ui.
- · Implemented chart based solutions using react-chart, chartis 2 for aggregating user data into friendly user readable form for data science and survey tools.

Imstrong Bangalore, India

- Part of founding engineering team along with one of co-founders as lead engineer.
- Implemented front end modules for core streaming product in react, WebRTC.
- · Converted photo-shop designs into HTML, CSS static pages and implemented the UI in react. · Implemented back-end API for the core product in node.js, express.js, Sequelize ORM and worked on lambda functions
- · Development a self running whats-app bot using python, selenium, SQLite by mimicking user interaction to send marketing messages.
- Implemented scripts in python for web scrapping for fetching data from web.
- Responsible for giving inputs on business solutions for the company thereby playing key role deciding company's path forward.

FEBRUARY 4, 2023 NAVEEN VIGNESH · RÉSUMÉ FRONT END DEVELOPER Nov. 2017 - Dec. 2018

Worked as front-end developer and mobile application developer as part of a team of three along with an external consultant for developing
react based solutions and react-native mobile applications.

- Part of the team which developed Recapp mobile application which is audio content delivery application used by teachers and students to listen and aggregate class audio content as well as student recitals of lessons.
- Part of the team which developed Raus mobile application which is used to provide tests for end users that are preparing for IAS exams. Contains features to aggregate video content and articles along with test packs for users to take up tests and view their performance data via charts
- Developed mobile application using react-native along with react-apollo graphql server less back-end.
- Implemented front-end modules using react on the core sass application of the company which is test portal aggregated to test centers for training students which includes stacks like react, C#, AWS, MySQL



HODL Real-Time Crypto Tracker

HODL Media Inc.

FRONT-END ENGINEER

Oct. 2022 - Current

- Developed modules for mobile application based on react-native stack.
- · Developed widget using native android and iOS stack with native bridge linking to react-native code.

Xponent applicationIntellect SEEC

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER Aug. 2022 - Current

- Revamped a web portal used for insurance underwriting originally written in Java server pages to Vue3 front end and nodejs back end
- · Written in Vue3 for handling front-end logic and wrote back end APIs in Node.js with Mongodb as database
- Uses primevue UI library provided by prime faces theme.
- Revamped the entire application from scratch maintaining the UX but with updating UI skin appearance.

iScan Mobile App Intellect SEEC

MOBILE APPLICATION DEVELOPER

Mar. 2022 - Jul. 2022

- Wrote a ionic mobile application with capacitor native core written in react-typescript with Android and iOS platforms for passport text recognition and data extraction
- Used tesseract and pytorch libraries for text recognization and object detection.
- Implemented ML logic in native android and ios using java and swift and used capacitor native bridge to reuse native functions.
- Build custom camera UI on Android and iOS native and reused it inside ionic typescript screens.
- Data models tesseract and pytorch to be used for passport and country id recognition was provided by data science team which was integrated into the application

ANZ Online Credit Profile

ANZ Bank (Client)

FRONT-END DEVELOPER Nov. 2020 - Current

- · Portal to enter and maintain credit information of clients and business that take credit line from the bank.
- · Written in react with typescript for front-end, uses C# and Java-Spring micro services for the back-end with MsSQL and MongoDB as databases.
- Uses reusable component library based on react-strap and storybook.
- · Implemented front-end modules, developed solutions in react from scratch based on business needs of the stack holders.
- Implemented back-end APIs for java spring micro services.

Imstrong Mobile App Imstrong

MOBILE APPLICATION DEVELOPER

Feb. 2020 - Dec. 2020

- $\bullet \ \ {\sf React-native\ application\ to\ implemented\ video\ content\ aggregation\ and\ live\ streaming\ of\ videos.}$
- Implemented modules to stream live video, play pre-recorded video content on the mobile
- Integrated web applications back-end APIs with auth token authentication in place of cookie based one in the web.
- Setup templates for the application to be published in app store and play store.

Imstrong Livestream Imstrong

FULL STACK DEVELOPER Jan. 2019 - Dec. 2020

- Imstrong live stream application used for conducting live classes.
- Implemented front-end modules in react, html, css3, sass.
- Implemented web-rtc module for one to one and one to many video chat module for live training feature of the product using WebRTC.
- Implemented APIs in node.js, Express for the backend service as per business needs.

Imstrong Courses Imstrong

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Jan. 2019 - Dec. 2020

- $\bullet \ \ \text{Imstrong courses is video content delivery module which is part of the company' web ecosystem.}$
- Implemented front-end modules in react, html, css3, sass.
- Implemented video streaming modules in react to stream HLS content.
- Implemented APIs in node.js, Express for back-end service for user usage details and authentication.
- · Implemented basic payment solution to implement course purchases using payment gateways like instamojo, payu.

Raus Brainvalley Software Pvt. Ltd.

MOBILE APPLICATION DEVELOPER Apr. 2018 - July. 2018

- React native mobile application used for providing quizzes and tests to end users preparing for IAS.
- Implemented front-end modules, developed solutions in react-native for application requirements.
- Used rest API that was available for web application for back-end service
- Implemented features like timers, charts, embedded web-view articles as part of the application features.
- · Used libraries like react-native-chart-toolkit for charts, react-native-keychain for token storage etc.

Recapp Brainvalley Software Pvt. Ltd.

MOBILE APPLICATION DEVELOPER

Jan. 2018 - Mar. 2018

- · React native mobile application used for aggregated audio content to be used in schools by students and teachers.
- Part of the team that developed the mobile application from scratch.
- Implemented front-end modules, developed solutions in react-native for application requirements.
- Used apollo-graphql with AWS Appsync and dynamo db for back-end service, AWS incognito for authentication.

react-native-otp-textinput

Open Source

CORE DEVELOPER Jul. 2018 - Current

- Re-usable OTP text input component developed for react-native
- Used react, react-native core libraries without any external dependencies.

Twitter based election prediction

Jaya Engineering College

DEVELOPER

Jan. 2018 - May. 2018

- College final project done on data analysis use techniques like sentimental analysis, linear regression to predict mood of election using twitter data.
- Used R framework and twitter API to extract and process data and used MongoDB database for data aggregation and storage
- Used a scientific base paper as the basis for the mathematics. applied when developing the analysis tool.

Honors & Awards

Feb. 2018 Winner, Debugging - Sagacia '17

Aug. 2017 Winner, IQ Ping (Quiz) - Nakshatra '17

Feb. 2017 Winner, Heal it - Fossage '17

Feb. 2017 Winner, Debate - Fossage '17

Chennai, India

Chennai, India

Chennai, India

Program Committees

2017 Secretary, Computer Society of India
 2016 Organizer, Android Workshop

Education

Jaya engineering college (Anna University Affiliated)

Chennai, India

B.E. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Aug. 2014 - May. 2018

Passed out with first class with an CGPA of 8.14

Extracurricular Activity

Smart India Hackathon 2019

Nagpur, India May. 2019

• Mentored college team of 6 people as alumni and team mentor.

Helped the team in developing video conferencing application based on react, node.js, WebRTC.

Smart India Hackathon 2018

Udaipur, India

Apr. 2018

Oct. 2017

Lead a team of 6 in SIH 2018.

TEAM | FADER

Теам Мемвек

- Developed a network assessing solution to find weakness in railway networks.
- Worked on framework like Nagios to implement a open source network monitoring tool for the Indian railways to be deployed in their IP networks.

SRM Hackathon Chennai, India

• Developed a data analysis script for analysing data related to food and consumption data sets.

- Worked on R framework to generate charts with based on likeness of food being consumed and top food being preferred by end users.
- FEBRUARY 4, 2023 NAVEEN VIGNESH · RÉSUMÉ

Chennai, India

TEAM LEADER Apr. 2017

- Lead a team of 6 and participated in the first Smart Indian Hackathon.
 Developed a mobile application in android that can alert end users when there is an earthquake that occurs.
 Was able to complete the prototype and provide a usable solution.